[Music]
mhm
hello there and welcome to my valley it
is frozen and quiet and yet there's so
much life everywhere
the paw prints of little rabbits dot the
snow and today i found evidence of the
very elusive moose
the winter birds are surprisingly active
now
seeking out the bird feeders townsfolk
leave on their lawns
january was the month of the wolf moon
paying homage to the many animals who
are hungry this time of year yet ever
patient for the first signs of spring
i'm looking forward to it as well though
my labrador and i are greatly enjoying
ourselves he loves to be outdoors even
more than i and he insists on pulling my
sled everywhere i think it feels like a
game of tug-of-war for him and it's
always so funny
maybe you are curled up in bed while
watching this traveling at work out in
nature somewhere else all together
wherever you are i hope that today
offers you some moments of joy be it the
moon rays the chortle of a bird or the
warmth of the sun on your neck
[Music]
i decided to start the morning reading
some texts
that were about spirituality but also
just mindfulness and and this paragraph
really stood out to me so i thought i
would read it to you at least paraphrase
it as best i can
we can choose to have an ancient
psychology that holds a refreshingly
positive view of human nature
our emotional difficulties are temporary
and more superficial instead of
all-consuming
we can choose to emphasize what is right
with us not what is wrong with us
and use that to inspire who we are for
example a more ancient psychology
acknowledges our disturbing emotions but
sees them as covering our essential
goodness
like clouds covering the sun
in this sense our darker moments and
most upsetting feelings are an
opportunity for uncovering a natural
wisdom
if we choose to look at it that way
by being attentive to our emotions we
can delve deeper into the moment
to perceive the little subtleties of
ordinary life
in this sense mindfulness creates a wise
attention to our days
a space of clarity that emerges when we
have a quiet mind
it makes us more receptive to the
whispers of our innate intuitive wisdom
i thought that was a very beautiful way
to talk about being mindful in your day
and
i will keep it in my heart today and try
to let it influence me because i was
feeling a little bit anxious this
morning being aware of all the things i
had to get done so that that's just
beautiful anyway i wanted to share it
with you and um yeah my tea has probably
gone cold so i'm gonna go warm it up
[Music]
today i was thinking about the past and
what advice i would give my younger self
the person i once was is so different
from who i am now
and something that really helped me feel
more at ease was changing the words i
speak to myself and to others
i wanted to hear your thoughts on this
because i think it is especially
relevant right now when we communicate
not only in person but online
[Music]
when i was younger newly graduated
working at a department store i had a
habit of defaulting to negative
statements when i was unhappy or
frustrated this was fed by feelings of
not having control over my life
feeling like a constant victim of
circumstance
i didn't like the person i was becoming
so negative and bitter
i worked a customer service position
that was quite stressful and all it
would take would be one rude customer to
ruin my day
sometimes customers would call me names
make fun of my job and even throw
tantrums and throw things sometimes
and if you work in customer service know
that i have the utmost respect for you
and all your hard work and patience it
is
not an easy job and often
underappreciated
[Music]
these memories of the past amuse me
because even though i would experience
the kindness of so many people
throughout my shift
i'd go home crying because of the single
angry customer who told me i would never
amount to anything
and yet by doing that i readily handed
over all my power and agency to them
pretty much welcoming them into my heart
and mind and letting them dictate the
rest of my day
that is something i've slowly worked on
changing realizing that i have the
choice to process experiences how i wish
and to my past self i will always say
take notice of the words you use
see them as having power over others but
most of all yourself
see them as little seeds that you're
holding in your heart and be careful
about which ones you water and allow to
grow
words have so much power and what we do
with the words we speak but also here
has a lot to do with how much we can
enjoy daily life in our own company or
that of others
[Music]
in celebration of another trip around
the sun and some excitement for the
spring and the longer days that are fast
approaching i decided to make a
spring-inspired embroidery pillow i've
never had much patience for needlework
so i did not have high expectations for
myself but considered it a wonderful
practice in mindfulness and slowness
and a wonderful way to just try
something new even if it doesn't come
out perfect i definitely made many
mistakes but i really enjoyed how it
turned out please let me know if you
have any craft projects in mind or
recipes that i should try because i'm
looking to learn new things all the time
[Music]
i once had a very good friend who loved
tea
and
she would heat up the water for her tea
drink her cup of tea and then spend the
next few hours just holding the teapot
and keeping warm
and i thought it was so funny and i
uh have been doing that a lot this
winter because it really works if you
just hold your teapot to you you feel
nice and warm and cozy it's actually
been quite a quiet week over here one of
my favorite times of the month is when
there's the full moon
because if you walk outside during the
full moon the moon rays dance across the
snow and glitter
it is just amazing like if you have
lived in a place with snow you know that
snow glitters at night when you shine
light on it but
to see the moonlight creating this kind
of shimmery cast over everything is
really magical i just love it so
yeah i'm looking forward to the next
full moon
so it'll be very beautiful for sure
anyway last but not least i did have a
question several months ago that a few
people reached out about and they were
wondering about a green dress that i
wore and have worn in some of my videos
and so i wanted to show it to you i will
put in some clips
it's not
i don't know if you can call it a dress
it is kind of inspired i think by a bit
of a sarong it's
a multi-use piece of fabric you can wear
it as a dress
but also a skirt
and i think you can even make it into a
sort of
short dress or shirt so
there's a lot of different ways to wear
it but
yeah i will show you a few i have not
been able to find anything like it
online unfortunately i have researched
for quite a while maybe i'm just not
using quite the right keywords
but it is a really wonderful piece of
clothing i
bought it when i was at a medieval fair
they were available and i actually have
seen them quite a few times available at
festivals and medieval fairs so maybe
that is the best place to go find them
but um yes it's it's just so beautiful
and light and airy and i love it
especially in the summer but also in the
winter when i'm inside and i'm doing a
lot of work around the house i'd love to
wear it as well
and
yeah so i i wish i could give you more
information on it
but i am sure that it is fairly easy to
sew it yourself
if you are someone that's handy with a
sewing machine
and um it might be worth a try but i
will give you an update once i know
where that's from
that was something very random but i had
quite a few people reach out and email
and message and all that so i did want
to address that unfortunately i just
don't know where it's from
but it is a really really fun dress so i
if anyone has any uh examples similar to
it please share them down below
anyway it has continued to be a nice
relaxing week
i had a little meeting this morning with
an editor to talk about changes to my
book that i'm working on and that was
really really exciting so i am going to
be working on that this week
working on orders working on a lot of
different things and i am also
continuing at the bookstore thank
goodness so i was very excited to be
doing that so i am able to help out
there every week
so
anyway i hope you all have a wonderful
day
and i will see you very very soon and i
will hopefully give you an update on the
housing situation very soon because we
are
trying to be approved for a loan so
we will see if we are but anyway sending
my love sending mr darcy's love and i
will see you soon goodbye
you